RG 166:003, Connecticut Abraham Lincoln Bicentennial Commission
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut Abraham Lincoln Bicentennial Commission records
2008-2010
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut Abraham Lincoln Bicentennial Commission
.25 cubic feet
The Connecticut Abraham Lincoln Bicentennial Commission was created to commemorate the bicentennial of Abraham Lincoln's birth by encouraging educational, historical and other organizations to develop Lincoln-related programs and events throughout the state from 2008 to February 12, 2010.
RG166_003
2011-018
Historical Note
The Connecticut Abraham Lincoln Bicentennial Commission was created to commemorate the bicentennial of Abraham Lincoln’s birth by encouraging educational, historical and other organizations to develop Lincoln-related programs and events throughout the state from 2008 to February 12, 2010. The commission coordinated its work with the National Bicentennial Commission, state and local agencies, as well as with historical and educational institutions.
Scope and Content
Includes membership list, correspondence and press releases, event listing and announcements, minutes and publications.
Index Terms
Organizations:
Connecticut Abraham Lincoln Bicentennial Commission
Subjects:
Lincoln, Abraham, 1809-1865 -- Anniversaries, etc; Connecticut Abraham Lincoln Bicentennial Commission -- Records and correspondence; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Anniversaries, etc; Connecticut -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Anniversaries, etc
Document Types:
Correspondence; DVDs; Minutes; Publications
Restrictions on Access
See the policy.
Provenance
These records were given to the Connecticut State Library on July 15, 2010 by Howard H. Wright, co-chair of the Commission.
Container List
- Records, 2008-2010
  - Commission organization and membership, 2008-2010 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Includes a copy of Gov. M. Jodi Rell's Executive Order 20 creating the Commission. An online copy of Executive Order 20 is available through
  - Correspondence and press releases, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Event listing and announcements, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Minutes and timeline, 2008-2009 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Publications, 2009-2010 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Abraham Lincoln Bicentennial Commission: Final report to Congress and the American people, 2010 April (Box 1, Folder 5)
      An online copy is available at
    - A new birth of freedom: Abraham Lincoln's bicentennial, 2009; 3 copies (Box 1, Folder 5)
      A copy is available at
    - Connecticut Lincoln Bicentennial Celebration 2009, DVD (Box 1, Folder 5)
      This item is separated from these records. Contact State Archives staff for assistance.
    - Poster from the Abraham Lincoln Bicentennial Commission and Foundation (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Working papers, 2008, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)